Welcome to the demonstration
video for the narcotic analgesic
PCA syringe preparation.
Please take time to look at your
procedural lab located in the
textbook.
Your instructor will provide the
narcotic CSP label with the
concentration that's ordered.
In this demonstration video, we
will prepare a concentration of
0.32 milligram per ML morphine
PCA.
We will draw up 16 milliliters
of a 1 milligram per mil
morphine and 34 milliliters of
preservative free normal saline.
The hood is set up so that we
have the sterile IPA swabs and
all of the ingredients that we
need for our PCA, the
preservative free normal saline,
and we'll be going into two
separate vials of our morphine.
We will open the first sterile
IPA 70% alcohol swab, and we'll
set that on the work service.
We'll take the cap off of our
normal saline, we'll open
another sterile IPA swab, and
we'll clean the stopper of that
vial.
We'll open the cap of our
morphine, we'll open a sterile
IPA swab.
We'll clean the stopper of that
vial and then we will continue
to open the 2nd vial of our
morphine.
We will wipe that off with that
sterile IPA swab.
We will peel back the packaging
of our syringe, making sure that
that tip stays in the air flow
from the HEPA filter.
We'll pee peel back the
packaging of the needle.
We'll recheck our connection.
We'll activate our syringe and
we'll pull back to the volume
that is in this first morphine
vial.
We're going to pull everything
out.
We're in a dark position.
We'll take that cap off and
place it on that IPA pad bevel
up, We'll go into the vial,
we'll invert that vial and we'll
begin the milking method.
Notice that all of our critical
sites are in the air flow from
the HEPA filter.
We don't need to worry about
troubleshooting air bubbles.
We're just going to get
everything out of this file.
We're going to cap the syringe
tap, slide, snap and then we're
going to pull back to the volume
that we need for our morphine.
We'll get back into a dark
position.
We'll take our cap and put it on
that sterile IPA pad, bevel up,
we'll go into our vial, we'll
invert the vial and then let's
go ahead and clear the bubbles
from the syringe.
You can use the air that's in
the syringe to get all those
micro bubbles by the stopper.
We'll tap against our work
surface and then we're in a
milking method.
We're going to bring that needle
tip into the liquid and then
we're going to get rid of all of
the air that's in the syringe
using the milking method.
And then we're going to make
sure that we have the volume
that we need for our PCA.
We're going to hold the barrel
will come out of the vial and
we'll go ahead and cap, tap,
slide, snap.
We're going to look for air
bubbles.
We're going to pull back on the
plunger tap, pull the plunger
back, tap, pull the plunger back
and then we're going to trap
that air into the hub of our
needle.
We're going to take a new
sterile IPA swab and we're going
to clean off the septum.
The stopper of our vial.
We want to be in a dart.
We'll take that cap off.
We'll be bevel up, We'll go into
our vial, we'll invert the vial
and then you want to push what
is in the hub and the lumen,
change your hand position will
come out to the volume that we
need and will come out of the
vial.
We'll tap, slide, snap that cap
on and then we'll ensure that we
have the 16 milliliters or the
volume that's ordered on your
CSP.
We're going to open a new
sterile IPA swab and place it on
the work surface.
We'll open a sterile IPA swab
and we'll open the stopper or
the septum of the vial.
We're going to get our syringe
and our needle.
We're going to open the outer
packaging of our syringe.
We're going to open our needle
packaging, ensuring that we
don't touch any critical sites.
We're going to activate our
syringe and we're going to pull
back to the volume of our
diluent, in this case 34 MLS.
We're going to get into a dart.
We're going to take our cap off
and put it on that IPA swab on
our work surface, bevel up,
we'll go into our vial, we'll
invert the vial and this time
we'll use the work surface to
help us do the milking method.
Notice that the critical sites,
our plunger that is pulled back
is now a critical site and then
where our needle and syringe
connection they're getting nice
air flow from the HEPA filter.
You want to make sure that that
needle tip is in liquid.
As we do our milking method, we
can see that there's some bubles
in our syringe and we're going
to clear those bubbles in just a
moment.
We'll use the work surface to
help us.
This time we're going to tap and
we can rotate the barrel so we
can see that we have cleared all
of those bubbles.
You can use the air that is in
the syringe to collect the rest
of those.
You want to bring your needle
tip in liquid and then we're
going to use the Milky method to
get rid of the rest of the air
that's in the syringe.
We'll let it equilibrate.
We're going to change our hand
position.
We have our 34 MLS.
We're going to come out of our
vial.
We'll cap our needle tap slide
snap and then double check that
we have that volume that we need
for our preservative free normal
saline.
Now we're going to use a lure to
lure connection and we're going
to open the packaging.
We don't have a cap on this.
So we're going to protect the
critical site by leaving the
packaging and we're going to
change the needle to our lure to
lure.
And then we want to be careful
with our hand position as we
connect the next syringe.
Note that the plunger is not
being touched and then we will
just change to that new syringe,
very similar to when we change
needles.
And then we're going to mix our
morphine so you can go back and
forth, make sure that you're not
touching any of your critical
sites.
We'll rotate our syringes so
that we're at 12 and six.
Now we need to clear that bubble
that was in that lure to lure
connection.
We'll push it up into that other
syringe and then we'll pull back
to our total volume of 50ML.
And then we're going to use
special caps for the PCA.
You can set your syringe down
and open those caps to expose
the cap, and then you want to
pull the barrel toward you to
come off that lure to lure
connection and then we'll go
into this tamper resistant cap.